export const ANIMALHUSBANDRYA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The true stomach of a goat is called",
A: "abomasum.",
B: "omasum.",
C: "reticulum.",
D: "rumen.",
answer: "A. abomasum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The causative organism of tuberculosis is a",
A: "bacterium.",
B: "fungus",
C: "protozoon.",
D: "virus.",
answer: "A. bacterium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following animal products is used in leather industry?",
A: "Egg",
B: "Hide",
C: "Hoof",
D: "Milk",
answer: "B. Hide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. I he recommended breeding ratio of male to female in rabbit production is",
A: "1:2.",
B: "1:4.",
C: "1:7.",
D: "1:10.",
answer: "B. 1:4",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. To avoid the outbreak of Newcastle disease on a poultry farm, chicks should be",
A: "culled.",
B: "isolated.",
C: "quarantined.",
D: "vaccinated.",
answer: "D. vaccinated",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Cooking pork properly is a way of eliminating",
A: "anthrax",
B: "nagana.",
C: "bladder worm",
D: "roundworm.",
answer: "C. bladder worm",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Piglets are given iron dextran in order to",
A: "improve appetite.",
B: "prevent anaemia.",
C: "prevent pneumonia.",
D: "improve digestibility.",
answer: "B. prevent anaemia",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The main advantage of keeping rabbits in their cages is to",
A: "reduce labour cost.",
B: "lower incidence of pests.",
C: "economize space.",
D: "lower incidence of diseases.",
answer: "D. lower incidence of diseases",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The most likely cause of death of a local hen near its eggs during incubation is",
A: "snake bite.",
B: "starvation.",
C: "chicken pox.",
D: "excessive heat.",
answer: "B. starvation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. If the weight of a duck increases from 0.4 kg to 2.4 kg in one month after consuming 6.0 kg of feed, determine the feed conversion ratio.",
A: "1:3",
B: "1:6",
C: "3:1",
D: "6:1",
answer: "A. 1:3",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following processes is not involved in artificial insemination?",
A: "Ejaculation",
B: "Mating",
C: "Ovulation",
D: "Teasing",
answer: "B. Mating",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The part labelled I could be removed for the following reasons: \nI. to increase floor space, \nII. promote self defense, \nIII. prevent injury.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following animals does not possess the part labelled",
A: "Boar",
B: "Bull",
C: "Ram",
D: "Wether",
answer: "D. Wether",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The part labelled 11 is called",
A: "croup.",
B: "dewlap.",
C: "hump.",
D: "rump.",
answer: "D. rump",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Advertisement of bacon could lead to",
A: "lower pricing of bacon.",
B: "increased demand for bacon.",
C: "promotion of pig production.",
D: "prevention of deterioration of bacon.",
answer: "B. increased demand for bacon",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following practices could be used to improve pastures in West Africa? \nI. Manuring \nII. Luning \nIII. Controlled burning",
A: "land II only",
B: "I and 111 only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I. II and m",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Livestock are starved for 10 to 18 hours before dewormers are administered in order to",
A: "make them swallow the dewormer.",
B: "kill the worms in a few hours.",
C: "make the dewormer effective.",
D: "calm them down.",
answer: "C. make the dewormer effective",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following practices could be used to improve local breeds of goats? \nI. Introduction \nII. Castration \nIII. Selection",
A: "1 and 11 only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and 111 only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following factors does not affect the quality of pasture?",
A: "Stocking rate",
B: "Leaf to stem ratio",
C: "Weather condition",
D: "Trampling",
answer: "D. Trampling",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following statements about cats is correct? They are",
A: "noisy animals.",
B: "nocturnal animals.",
C: "susceptible to coccidiosis.",
D: "used for home security.",
answer: "B. nocturnal animals",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The scolex is associated with",
A: "mites.",
B: "roundworms.",
C: "tapeworms.",
D: "ticks.",
answer: "C. tapeworms",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The function of an electro-ejaculator during artificial insemination is to",
A: "collect semen.",
B: "service the female.",
C: "induce semen release",
D: "induce heat in the animal",
answer: "C. induce semen release",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Determine the value of X.",
A: "0.60%",
B: "0.80 %",
C: "75.20 %",
D: "99.20%",
answer: "B. 0.80 %",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. What percentage of the milk is total solid?",
A: "3.90%",
B: "7.25 %",
C: "12.00%",
D: "12.80%",
answer: "B. 7.25 %",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. If 1200 kg of milk is produced per lactation, determine the water content.",
A: "144.00 kg",
B: "153.60 kg",
C: "1046.40 kg",
D: "1056.00 kg",
answer: "C. 1046.40 kg",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The nutrient in milk responsible for building new tissues is",
A: "carbohydrate.",
B: "fat.",
C: "protein.",
D: "minerals.",
answer: "C. protein",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following groups of feed stuff could be used as concentrate?",
A: "Fish meal, straw, groundnut cake",
B: "Fish meal, silage, cassava meal",
C: "Groundnut cake, meat meal, straw",
D: "Groundnut cake, fish meal, cassava meal",
answer: "D. Groundnut cake, fish meal, cassava meal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following forage is a leguminous plant?",
A: "Cynodon dactylon",
B: "Andropogon gayanus",
C: "Ageratum conyzoides",
D: "Pueraria Phaseoloides",
answer: "D. Pueraria Phaseoloides",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The scrotum in a bull helps in",
A: "attracting cows for mating.",
B: "ensuring successful castration of the bull.",
C: "providing adequate oxygen to the testes.",
D: "regulating the temperature around the testes. ^ ^",
answer: "D. regulating the temperature around the testes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following diseases of pigs could be effectively controlled by slaughtering and burying?",
A: "Anthrax",
B: "Swine dysentery",
C: "Hog cholera",
D: "Gastro-enteritis",
answer: "C. Hog cholera",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following diseases of poultry is caused by nutrient deficiency?",
A: "Newcastle disease",
B: "Pneumonia",
C: "Gumboro",
D: "Rickets",
answer: "D. Rickets",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following structures serves as a shock absorber for growing foetus?",
A: "Amnion",
B: "Cervix",
C: "Placenta",
D: "Uterus",
answer: "A. Amnion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Farm animals are starved before slaughtering in order to",
A: "reduce the pain at slaughtering.",
B: "make it easy to detect infectious diseases.",
C: "prevent faecal contamination of the meat.",
D: "make the meat tender for consumption.",
answer: "C. prevent faecal contamination of the meat",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following management practices correctly matches the animal on which it is carried out?",
A: "Debeaking → duck",
B: "Docking → fowl",
C: "Grooming → snail",
D: "Tattooing → cattle",
answer: "D. Tattooing → cattle",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The pricing of beef cattle in West Africa is usually based on",
A: "dental formula.",
B: "size of animal.",
C: "number of teats.",
D: "length of tail.",
answer: "B. size of animal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following statements about pastures are correct? \nI. It is easily digested \nII. It contains more cellulose \nIII. It supplies cheaper feed",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the tools are used during the construction of a rabbit hutch?",
A: "I, II and IV only",
B: "I, II and III only",
C: "II, III only IV only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "A. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The tool labelled III is called",
A: "scissors.",
B: "pliers.",
C: "burdizzo.",
D: "shears.",
answer: "D. shears",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Livestock could be restrained during",
A: "dehorning and watering",
B: "open castration and dehorning.",
C: "dehorning and parturition",
D: "open castration and parturition.",
answer: "B. open castration and dehorning",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. If the hatchability of ostrich eggs is 70%, determine the number of chicks that could be hatched from 4000 fertile eggs set in an incubator.",
A: "1200 chicks",
B: "2800 chicks",
C: "3930 chicks",
D: "4000 chicks",
answer: "B. 2800 chicks",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. When birds of different ages are reared in the same pen, it could result in \nI. cannibalism, \nII. starvation, \nIII. overcrowding.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following organs are part of the female reproductive system? \nI. Ovary \nII. Seminal vesicle \nIII. Fallopian tube",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The system in which chickens are reared in movable wooden units is known as",
A: "slatted wooden system.",
B: "battery cage system.",
C: "deep litter system.",
D: "fold system.",
answer: "D. fold system",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. When temperatures are within the thermoneutral zone, egg production in layers is expected to be",
A: "decreasing.",
B: "fluctuating.",
C: "highest.",
D: "lowest.",
answer: "C. highest",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following farm animals could produce food without being slaughtered?",
A: "Duck",
B: "Grasscutter",
C: "Pig",
D: "Rabbit",
answer: "D. Rabbit",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Oyster shell is included in feed of farm animals because it",
A: "provides energy.",
B: "helps to prevent rickets.",
C: "is a rich source of vitamins.",
D: "provides iron for blood formation.",
answer: "B. helps to prevent rickets",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. During incubation of chicken eggs, candling is done on days",
A: "7 and 18.",
B: "9 and 14.",
C: "11 and 18.",
D: "15 and 19.",
answer: "A. 7 and 18",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Deamination of amino acids takes place in the",
A: "bile duct.",
B: "liver.",
C: "lungs.",
D: "skin.",
answer: "B. liver",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The genetic make-up of an organism is described as its",
A: "chromosome.",
B: "genotype.",
C: "phenotype.",
D: "trait.",
answer: "B. genotype",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The atlas vertebra is located",
A: "in the sternum.",
B: "within the pelvic girdle.",
C: "between the skull and the axis vertebra.",
D: "between the last lumber vertebra and die sacrum.",
answer: "C. between the skull and the axis vertebra",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]